你正被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people,
像你一样的普通人
people like you,
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第19集
Person of Interest S01E19 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
有时候我会想  如果她没有被杀
Sometimes I wonder what kind of man I'd be
我会变成怎样的人呢
if she hadn't been killed.
我听说失去父母后  人会改变
I hear people change when they lose a parent,
特别是如果其父母死于谋杀
especially when that parent is murdered.
今天有个大考  对吧
Big test today, right?
我以前恨死代数了
I always hated algebra.
那些什么x啊y啊搞得我稀里糊涂
All those xs a ys made my head spin.
我对那个倒无所谓
I don't mind it so much.
你想跟我谈谈吗
Hey, you wanna talk about it?
-没什么大事  -看起来可不像
- It's no big deal. - It seems like it might be.
只是某些阔佬傻逼为我拿奖学金的事
It's just some rich d-bag's giving me a hard time
-给我难堪了  -告诉我是谁
- for being on scholarship. - I wanna know who they are.
-不要  -泰勒
- No way. - Taylor.
我最不喜欢你掺和这种事情
Last thing I need is you fighting my battles.
我不是小孩子了
I'm not some little kid.
今晚我坐地铁回家
I'll take the subway home tonight.
我知道你要工作到很晚
I know you're working late.
-晚上吃泰式炒面  -好
- Pad Thai for dinner? - Yeah.
祝你今天愉快
Have a good day, okay?
卡特
Carter.
我是科调司的拉布兰卡
It's Lablanca in S.I.D.
准备迎接我给予的快乐时光吧
You ready for me to make your day?
你是要说我赢得去夏威夷的带薪假了吧
You're about to tell me I won a paid vacation to Hawaii?
差不多了
Almost as good.
还记得那些你认为属于以利亚的账户吧
You know those accounts you thought belonged to Elias?
几星期前我们追踪到的投资银行吗
The ones we traced to that investment firm a few weeks ago?
你发现那些账户的时候
When you flagged those accounts,
里边有4百万美元的余额
they had a balance of $4 million.
而到了今天早上  一分钱不剩了
As of this morning, not a dime.
以利亚把账户提空了  卡特  全提空了
Elias drained them, Carter. All of them.
我十分钟内赶到
I'll be there in ten minutes.
来得可有点晚啊  里瑟先生
Bit of a late start, Mr. Reese.
你忘了上闹钟了吗
Did you forget to set your alarm?
上瑜伽课去了
Had my yoga class.
好吧  希望你保持真气充盈
Well, I hope you've gotten in touch with your Chi
因为今天可有得受了
because it seems we have a big day ahead of us.
今早收到了五个号码
We received five numbers this morning.
大丰收啊
Bumper crop.
来见识下五大家族的首领
Meet the heads of the five families.
卡帕雷利
Caparelli.
桑布拉诺  格里福尼
Zambrano. Grifoni.
巴西莱
Basile.
吉亚尼・莫雷蒂二世
Gianni Moretti Jr.
莫雷蒂的儿子
Moretti's son.
莫雷蒂进监狱后他儿子开始管事
Junior took over when Moretti went to prison.
除非是这些人突然决定
Unless all these men suddenly decided
要开始内讧
to turn on one another,
我认为比较合理的假设是  他们被人盯上了
I think it's fair to assume that they're being targeted.
疯狂到敢对全体黑手党头目下手的人
Short list of people crazy enough to take on
数量不会很多
the entire leadership of the Cosa Nostra.
就我看来  只有一个
Only one, in my opinion.
以利亚
Elias.
他已经绑架了自己的父亲
He's already kidnapped his father.
除掉剩下的几个头目
Eliminate the remaining dons,
他就能掌管整个黑帮了
he could control the entire mafia.
我不确定  芬奇
I don't know, Finch.
我们可以让他们黑吃黑
We could let the trash take out the trash.
我知道你在中情局工作时  他们会鼓励纵容
I know they encouraged a certain moral flexibility
你"从权"的道德观  里瑟先生
when you worked at the CIA, Mr. Reese,
但我以为  我们要有更高的道德标准
but I like to think that we're reaching for a higher standard
无论如何
In any case,
我们都要考虑到间接伤害
we need to consider the collateral damage.
那我们就得给这五位纽约市最有权势的罪犯
So we're going to babysit the five most powerful criminals
当回保姆了
in New York.
怎么接近他们呢
How do we get close to them?
这些先生们每个月会在
These gentlemen meet once a month
布鲁克林的盟约俱乐部聚会一次
at the covenant club in Brooklyn.
私人会议室里面没有摄像头
There are no cameras allowed inside the private meeting room
也不许带手机
and no cell phones.
想要监视这些家伙可不容易
Not gonna be easy to spy on these guys.
对你来说也一样  芬奇
Not even for you, Finch.
好像在对我下战书啊  里瑟先生
That sounds like a challenge, Mr. Reese.
俱乐部最近重新安装了一套消防警报系统
The club recently installed a new fire alarm system.
紧急情况下  消防员能够
In case of emergency, fire fighters could communicate
与被困其中的人通过声音系统交流
with anyone trapped inside through a sound system.
但是通过转换电极  任何话筒
But any speaker can be converted to a crude microphone
都能变成简单的麦克风
by reversing polarity.
那些国土安全部的白痴们
Those idiots from the Department of Homeland Security,
连贿赂都不会收
they can't even take a bribe right.
出货只有原定的二分之一
That shipment was half of what it was supposed to be.
现在怎么办
What are we gonna do with it?
干得漂亮  芬奇
Nice work, Finch.
咱们得加快速度
We'll step on it more than usual.
如果顾客要投诉
If the customers complain,
可以投进意见箱里
they can put a note in our suggestion box.
你们开什么玩笑
You kidding me with this?
生意照常  就当什么也没发生吗
Business as usual like nothing's changed?
我们对你父亲的际遇感到抱歉  二世
We're all very sorry for your father's situation, Junior.
际遇
Situation?
我父亲可能都已经死了
My father's probably dead.
我想知道家族准备如何
I wanna know what the family's gonna do to retaliate
报复以利亚
against this Elias.
你是说你同父异母的哥哥
You mean your half-brother?
你老子自找的
Your old man brought this on himself.
他射出了那混球  然后又架不住丢人
He sired a little bastard and then he had the poor taste
干掉那当妈的
to have the mother bumped off.
这是无耻的谎言
That's a filthy lie.
无意冒犯  二世
No disrespect, Junior.
我们不在乎你要不要请以利亚来欢度感恩节
We don't care if you bring Elias over for Thanksgiving.
他是个明白人  能给我们带来钱
He's a player, brings in a lot of cash.
你们居然想跟他合作  你们明知道他抢劫你
You wanna work with a man that you know is robbing you?
还吞食了我们的地盘
And stealing our territories?
这是生意  又不是谈情说爱
It's a business, kid. It's not a love affair.
跟他合作
We work with him,
我们都能赚大钱
we all get rich.
我们得告诉这些先生们
We need to convey to these gentlemen
以利亚没兴趣跟他们做交易
that Elias won't be interested in making a deal.
我以为该通知卡特警探了
I think it's time to update Detective Carter.
有难度  她现在都不跟我们说话了
That could be difficult, since she's not speaking to us.
一声道歉  大有裨益  里瑟先生
An apology might go a long way, Mr. Reese.
如果以利亚把钱都转移走了
If Elias moved all of his money,
那转到哪儿去了呢
where did it go?
我暂时也没头绪
I don't know yet.
款项流向了1000个不同的客户
The funds went out to over 1,000 unique payees.
拿到其中某一位的姓名了吗
Did you get any names of the people he paid?
没那么容易
It's not that easy.
是啊  对付这家伙就没容易过
Yeah, it never is with this guy.
除了现金就是银行电汇
Everything's going out as cash or wire transfers.
我们能追踪到
We could trace it,
但是光申请到搜查证就要几周的时间
but the warrants alone would take a couple weeks.
你认为他都买了些什么
What do you think he's buying?
以利亚才不在乎物质
Elias doesn't care about material things.
他收买的是人
He buys people.
甘愿为钱杀人的人
People who'll murder for money.
睁只眼闭只眼的警察和政客们
Cops and politicians who'll look the other way.
不管他买的是什么  数量巨大
Well, whatever it is, he just bought a lot of it.
你得用手抓着吃了
You'll have to eat with your hands.
我还记得你以前可是使刀高手
I remember you were pretty good with a knife back in the day.
他们叫你"刀锋战士"  对吧
They called you "The Blade", right?
我永远都理解不了你们那一代人  还有
I never understood your generation and...
你们那些搞笑的绰号
the ridiculous nicknames.
你们虚度光阴  慢慢变得脑满肠肥
You spent too much time growing fat.
软弱无力
Soft.
其中一些甚至想把家族生意合法化
Some of them even tried to turn the family legit,
比如你儿子
like your son.
我是说  你真正的儿子
I mean, your real son.
你为什么不直接杀了我
Why don't you just kill me already?
我可不想你错过好戏
I would hate for you to miss the show.
我要完成你一直没种动手的事情
I'm gonna do what you never had the stones to.
我会联合这些家族  控制一切
I'm gonna unite the families, and take control.
无名小卒的痴心妄想
That's some plan for a nobody.
你真认为我的同伙们会跟着你
And you think my associates are gonna go along
折腾这场闹剧吗
with this farce?
他们没有选择
They won't have a choice.
还有  我从来就不懂分享
Besides, I never learned how to share.
我母亲应该教教我
My mother might have taught me,
不过她没有机会  不是吗
but she didn't get the chance, did she?
45分钟赶到皇后区  我可是有正经活儿的
45 minutes to Queens? I got a real job, you know.
HR才是你的正经活儿  弗斯科
HR is your real job, Fusco.
我需要点情报
I need some intel on that guy
有个人老是在城里搅事
who's been stirring things up around town.
一个高个子西装男
Tall guy with a suit.
老喜欢打穿别人的膝盖
Likes shooting people in the kneecaps.
这不是旧闻了吗
I thought he was yesterday's news.
联帮探员可不这样想
Not to the feds.
他们新建了一个专案组负责找他
They set up a new task force trying to locate him.
我们需要所有组内动向
We wanna know everything they do,
想自己先找到他
see if we can get to him ourselves.
怎么  你们要拉拢他吗
Why, you looking to put him on the payroll?
你问题太多了  弗斯科
You ask a lot of questions, Fusco.
哥有一颗刨根问底的心啊
I got an inquisitive mind.
我们现在给以利亚干活
We're doing a job for Elias.
什么时候HR给以利亚干活了
Since when does HR work for Elias?
我们不为任何人干活
We don't work for anybody.
我们有奶就是娘
We lend a hand when it's in our best interest.
现在以利亚有奶
Right now that's Elias.
等你完成任务
When you're done looking into that matter,
最好请病假
I'd call in sick.
接下来这几天  你可不会想在凶案组上班
You don't wanna be working Homicide next couple of days.
你确定这是最佳行动方案吗
Are you certain this is the best course of action?
黑手党们对于不请自来的人
Mafiosi don't take kindly to people who approach them...
不甚友善
unannounced.
会表现得像狗急跳墙
They're like feral dogs that way.
没时间磨叽  只能单刀直入  芬奇
No time for anything but the direct approach, Finch.
还有  我对付狗相当有一套
Besides, I've always been good with dogs.
怎么  迷路了吗
What are you, lost?
我来提醒你们一下以利亚的事儿
I'm here to give you a heads up about Elias.
他自有算盘
He's got plans.
可没预你们几位的位置
And they don't include you and your friends.
-你是警察吗  -边都挨不上
- You a cop? - Not even close.
坦白说  我可不介意
Frankly, I'd be inclined
你们这群蠢货自相残杀
to let you idiots kill each other,
不过那样会惹出麻烦
But that could get messy.
你的人没法保护你
Your men here can't protect you.
但是我可以  只要你们跟我来
But I can. If you come with me.
多谢关心  朋友  不过
Thanks for your concern, my friend, but...
我不需要你的帮助
I don't need your help.
我被三振了  芬奇  卡帕雷利不听我的
I struck out, Finch. Caparelli wouldn't listen to me.
发生什么事了  里瑟先生
What happened, Mr. Reese?
以利亚找上他了  芬奇
Elias got to him, Finch.
间接伤害这点你算是说对了
You were right about collateral damage.
我希望他们死  全都死光
I wish they were dead. All of them.
-发生了什么  卡尔  -他们先挑头的
- What happened, Carl? - They started it.
骂我
Calling me names.
比彻女士说你的期末报告一直没交
Ms. Beecher told me you never turned in your term project.
因为那期末报告太蠢了
That's 'cause it was stupid.
是这个吗
Is this it?
我不是私生子
I'm not a bastard.
你是为这个和他们打架的吗
Is that why you fought them?
谁那么叫你
Who called you that?
来  我帮你填完剩下的
Come on, I'll help you fill out the rest.
填些什么  这是家谱
With what? It's for family.
卡尔・以利亚  你有我
Well, Carl Elias, you got me.
还有你的养姐妹
And your foster sisters.
我有妈妈
I had a mother.
她去世了
She's gone.
或许我们可以调查一下
Maybe we could do some research,
找到更多名字填上去
find some more names to fill in.
比如我爸爸吗
Like my father?
亲爱的
H-honey...
你肯定知道些什么  他是谁
You must have heard something about him, who he was--
卡尔  拜托
Carl, do me a favor.
别纠结了
Let it go.
你觉得他知道
Do you think he even knows
妈妈身上发生的事吗
about what happened to my mom?
据我所知  宝贝
Here's what I know, baby.
我们每个人都是国王的后裔
We are all descended from kings.
你必须走自己的路
You gotta live your own life.
做自己的王
Be your own man.
明白了吗
You understand?
我正想你什么时候会打来呢  约翰
I was wondering when you'd call, John.
听说你下午目睹了一场惨剧
I heard you witnessed the tragedy earlier this afternoon.
希望你没在爆炸中受伤
I hope you weren't hurt from the explosion.
以利亚
Elias...
停手吧  别再伤害更多人了
End this before anyone else gets hurt.
我只是做了我认为最有利于这个城市的事
I'm only doing what I think is best for the city.
所以你要干掉每个挡你路的人吗
So you're gonna kill everyone who gets in the way?
虽然你不愿承认  但我们是同一类人
We're more alike than you'd like to admit.
都不惜杀人
Both killers in our own right.
不过现在你要救的是查理・伯顿那样的无辜者
But now you save innocent people like Charlie Burton,
而不是那些老黑帮
Not old gangsters.
就把他们留给我好了
Just leave those men to me.
你知道我不会那么做
You know I can't do that.
不出所料
I can't say I'm surprised.
回见吧
See you on the other side.
还有个麻烦  卡特警探
We have another problem. Detective Carter.
我还以为她没接电话
I thought she wasn't answering her calls.
是没接
She wasn't.
不过你知道的  我总能
But as you know, I've always taken
善用手机的各种功能
a somewhat liberal view of how to use a telephone.
她知道以利亚在计划些什么
She knows that Elias is up to something.
卡帕雷利被杀后  她开始联系
After Caparelli's murder, she started reaching out
其余的黑帮头目  要为他们提供警方保护
to the remaining dons, offering them police protection.
她不知道以利亚
She doesn't know that Elias
是要马上把他们全干掉
is planning to take them all out at once.
也不知道以利亚有HR的协助
Or that he's got HR's backing.
把她的位置给我  快
I need her location. Now.
你们跟我来
You come with me.
剩下的人封锁这个街区
The rest of you lock down both ends of the block
直到我们把这个人带走  明白了吗
until we get this guy out of here, understood?
我们要接谁啊  警探
Who are we bringing in, detective?
黑帮头目巴西莱
Don Basile.
我们抓到以利亚之前
He's going into protective custody
对他进行保护性监禁
until we can take down Elias.
-你是卡特吗  -是
- You carter? - Yeah.
我怎么知道不是以利亚雇你来的
How am I supposed to know you're not on Elias's payroll?
你是不知道
You can't.
你要是有别的选择  那就别听我的
You got another option, I recommend you take it.
否则  就跟我走吧
Otherwise, let's move.
好吧  走  走
All right, come on, come on.
警探
Detective...
人都去哪儿了
Where'd everyone go?
退后
Get back.
快退后
Get back!
你真应该接电话的  警探
You really should return your calls, detective.
这些是新的盗版光碟  老大
Those new bootleg CDs, boss.
卢的车箱里还有更多
We got a whole bunch more in Lou's trunk.
等等  孩子
Hold on a second, kid.
我要跟他聊几句
I'd like a word, please.
也许我该留下  爸爸
Maybe I should stay, pop.
回家去  告诉你妈妈我已经吃过了
Go home, tell your mother I already ate.
可是  爸爸  我觉得...
But, pop, I was just thinking--
你是卢介绍来的  对吗
You came to us through Lou, right?
是的  先生
That's right, sir.
问题是  我并不太了解你  孩子
Thing is, I don't know much about you, kid,
不过你看起来很眼熟
But you look familiar.
再联系下名字  以利亚
Along with the name. Elias.
我想你明白我的意思
I think you know what I mean.
我的妈妈是玛琳・以利亚  先生
My mother was Marlene Elias, sir.
我想也是
I thought so.
美丽的女人
Beautiful woman.
据说是的  先生
I've been told that, sir.
我曾经想过这一天来临的时候
I thought about when this day might come.
我会对你说些什么
What I would say to you.
你来这儿做什么  孩子  你想要我做什么
What are you doing here, kid? What do you want from me?
我只想要一份工作  先生
I just want a job, sir.
一个向高手学习的机会
A chance to learn from the best.
来证明自己
To prove myself.
你知道钻石是怎么形成的吗  孩子
You know where diamonds come from, kid?
开始只是块碳
Starts out as carbon.
黑如煤  深埋在地球深处
Black as coal, buried miles beneath the earth.
承受重压  炙烤于比地狱更热的温度
Takes pressure, temperatures hotter than hell.
数以亿年  直到火山喷发
Billions of years, until a volcano
将其喷至地球表面
blows it to the surface.
这是成就一颗钻石的唯一途径
That is the only way to form a diamond.
从来没听说过
Never heard that before.
我也从不知道我父亲是谁
I didn't know my father either.
我活下来了
I survived.
我不知道这些  先生
I didn't know that, sir.
但是...
But...
你会来此是因为你明白了某些事情
You're here because you figured some things out.
所以你我之间
So now you and me,
有了自己的小秘密
we have our own little secret.
他们告诉我你很有两下子  孩子
They tell me you got a pair, kid.
坚忍不拔  精明能干
Tenacious. Capable.
-不胜荣幸  先生  -抬起头来
- I like to think so, sir. - You keep your head up.
这儿有你的一席之地
There's a place for you here.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
很高兴终于跟你见面了
So nice to finally meet you.
那个警官情况已经稳定了
The officer's stable.
我们很幸运  你出现的正是时候
Lucky for us, you got good timing.
我想你已经知道了
I guess you should know,
联邦调查局特地为你成立了个特别小组
the FBI has a new task force set up in your honor.
他们认为你在为以利亚做事
They think you're working with Elias.
我经常被误解
I'm often misunderstood.
看来巴斯勒先生的事情未如所期
I take it things didn't go as expected with Mr. Basile.
我都不知道该相信谁了
I don't know who to trust anymore.
你可以相信我们...
You can trust us...
警探
Detective.
以利亚在过去48小时里把4百万美金
Elias transferred $4 million in the past 48 hours
转到了全市的数十处提现点
to a dozen cash and carry hubs around the city.
我们可以用这些转账记录追踪到
We could use those transfers to track down
为他做事的人  但...
the men working for him, but...
没有搜查证我没法进入他们的数据库
I can't access their database without a warrant.
也许我可以动用  另一种技术
Maybe I could use...other techniques...
查到我们所需要的信息
to access the information we need.
如果我们从以利亚的付款单顺藤摸瓜
If we track down the men on Elias's payroll,
也许能直接查到他本人
they may lead us right to him.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我还得说服那帮黑帮老大们
I need to convince those old dons
如果想活命的话就得跟我们合作
that the only way to stay alive is to work with us.
多谢这次的支援
Thanks for the backup.
如果下次我不能赶到
If I'm not there next time...
我希望你有所准备
I want you to be prepared.
这可不是标准制式武器
Not exactly standard issue.
我该问问你从哪儿弄到这些的吗
Should I ask where you got these?
最好不要问
Probably best if you don't.
你准备重返伊拉克还是怎么着
You getting shipped back to Iraq or something?
我需要个帮手
I need an assist.
我让你多带的防弹衣和弹药带了没
Did you bring the extra vest and ammo like I told you?
带了
Yeah.
上车
Just get in.
你是我现在唯一能信任的警察了
You're the only cop I can trust right now.
我跟的是什么人  芬奇
Who am I looking at, Finch?
我查了从以利亚账户转出的
I was able to trace the financial transactions
财务交易记录
coming out of Elias's accounts.
你跟的就是其中一个收款人
The man you're following is one of the recipients.
以利亚的付款单就像
Elias's payroll reads
美国刑事系统名人录
like a who's who of the US penal system.
我在跟着他
I'm following him.
那他在跟着谁
But who's he following?
是一家人
It's a family.
知道他们是谁吗
Any idea who they are?
也许他们和黑帮头目们有关
Maybe they're related to the dons.
以利亚可不惮威胁别人的挚爱
Elias isn't above threatening their loved ones.
理论正确
Right theory.
对象错误
Wrong organization.
以利亚的人在跟踪HR的家人  芬奇
Elias's people are following HR families, Finch.
我不明白他的策略
I don't understand his strategy.
HR跟他是一边的
HR are his allies.
在战争里  你必须像掌控敌人一般
In war, you need to be able to coerce your allies
牢牢掌控你的同盟
every bit as much as your enemies.
也就是说任何一名警方的内应
Which means if any of his law enforcement contacts
出了问题  他都有备用计划
gets out of line, he has a backup plan.
要我也这么做
That's what I would do.
如果你从一开始就听我的
If you had listened to me to begin with
我们就能在他绑架我父亲之前抓到他
we could have gotten him before he went after my father.
警探
Detectives.
什么风把你们吹来我们这个小俱乐部了
What's so important you bully your way into our club?
你们被保护性监禁了
You're going into protective custody
直到找到以利亚为止
until we can find Elias.
没这个必要吧
I don't think so.
这不是跟你们商量
It's not really up for discussion.
你搞不定他
You've failed to control this man.
你们有人企图跟他做交易
Some of you tried to cut deals with him.
结果现在他在追杀你们
And now he's coming after you.
我不会任由无辜民众惨遭杀害
I'm not gonna stand by and let innocent civilians get killed
就因为你们这些人无视眼前的事实
because you chose to ignore what was right in front of your nose.
吉米
Jimmy!
送警探们出去
Come show the detectives out.
你在干嘛  睡着了吗
What are you, sleeping?
吉米
Jimmy!
看来你们的小弟都抛弃了你们
Looks like your boys abandoned you.
想赌赌看以利亚的人是否就在不远处吗
You wanna bet Elias's men aren't far behind?
我们不和条子合作
We don't work with cops.
你们不想自愿跟我们走吗
You don't wanna come voluntarily,
那我们就要来硬的了
we're gonna take you by force.
你准备开枪打我吗
What are you gonna shoot us?
如果我打死你  那也许以利亚
If I shoot you, then maybe Elias
就不用炸飞整车的无辜市民
won't have to blow up a carload of innocent people.
我们要不要叫支援
Hey, shouldn't we call for backup?
你就是我的支援
You are my backup.
以利亚的人来了
Here come Elias's guys.
你好
Hello?
找你的
It's for you.
你好
Hello?
左转过两条街后去总统大街954号
Turn left and go two blocks to 954 president street.
真及时
You got good timing.
-下个路口左转  弗斯科  -上二楼
- Next left, Fusco. - Go to the second floor.
-密码是3288  -收到
- The code is 3288. - Got it.
这是谁的地方
Who owns this place again?
一个朋友
A friend.
你真有些诡异的朋友  卡特
You got some weird friends, Carter.
我不太记得我妈妈了
I don't remember a lot about my mom.
她死的时候我只有四岁
I was four when she died.
当然  这些你都知道
Of course, you know that.
但我经常想起一些她的片段
But every so often I get these images of her,
特别是当我闻到她的香水味时
especially when I smell her perfume.
应该是"一千零一夜"
Shalimar, I think.
娇兰经典款香水
她有着黝黑的秀发
She had dark hair.
和蔼的眼神
Kind eyes.
其它的时候我只能想起那些血
Other times I just see the blood.
那么娇小的人  却流了那么多的血
Just so much blood from such a small person.
出了点问题  老大
There was a problem, boss.
那个警探  你想要干掉的那个
The detective-- the one you wanted gone.
她带走了他
She took him.
-哪个人  -所有人
- Which one? - All of them.
知道了
I see.
这次我们需要警方的朋友
We'll need our friends on the police force
跟我们合作了
to join us on this one.
卡特和弗斯科警探都安然无恙地
Detectives Carter and Fusco are both safe and sound
待在我的地盘  里瑟先生
at one of my properties, Mr. Reese.
剩下的黑帮头目们也在
As are the remaining dons.
很好  芬奇
Good to hear, Finch.
她怎么说服他们和她走的
How'd she convince him to go with her?
她没有  她直接绑架了他们
She didn't. She kidnapped them.
看来她受你影响了  里瑟先生
It seems you've had something of an influence on her, Mr. Reese
多谢夸奖  芬奇
Thanks, Finch.
我可不是在表示赞赏
I'm not certain I meant that as a compliment.
以利亚不会善罢甘休的  芬奇
Elias isn't gonna take this lying down, Finch.
还没他的线索  但我已经锁定了他很多手下
No sign of him yet, but I've tracked down a dozen of his men
他们都处于一旦事情有变  可以随时攻击
All positioned to strike against the families of HR cops
HR警察家人的位置
if things don't go his way.
幸好HR不知道黑帮头目们何在
Luckily HR doesn't know where the Dons are.
只有卡特和弗斯科知道
Only Carter and Fusco do.
芬奇
Finch...
我们跟踪的人中
The men that we're tracking...
有没有正在布鲁克林马伯里高中附近的
Are any of them near Marbury high school in Brooklyn?
有  怎么了
Yes, why?
卡特的儿子在那里上学
That's where Carter's son goes to school.
是什么事故  我妈妈没事吧
What was the accident? Is my mom gonna be all right?
现在还说不准
It's too soon to tell.
不过我会马上带你去医院
But I'll take you right to the hospital.
未知号码
-喂  -泰勒
- Hello? - Taylor?
你不认识我  但你现在有危险
You don't know me, but you are in danger
你必须待在学校里
and I want you to stay inside the school
找个老师陪着你  等我们过去
with a teacher until we can get to you.
泰勒
Taylor?
别出声  否则要你好看
Just keep quiet, and you won't get hurt.
出示你的通行证
Hey, I need to see your pass!
我们得在这里待多久
How long you think we can stay here?
待到确定他们安全
Until we know they're safe.
他们可是黑帮老大  卡特
They're mob bosses, Carter.
可有的等了
That ain't gonna happen any time soon.
没搞错吧
You've gotta be kidding me.
以利亚的手下是怎么找到我们的
How did Elias's men find us?
我还以为你把他们甩开了
I thought you shook them off.
我甩开了  甩得干干净净
I did, we were free and clear.
有什么消息
What do you have?
卡特  我得告诉你件事
Carter, I need to tell you something.
你一定要知道  我不会让他出事的
You've gotta know I'm not gonna let anything happen to him.
明白吗  我会找到他的
You understand? I'll find him.
找到谁  发生什么事了  约翰
Find who? What's going on, John?
来电
泰勒
Taylor?
你有个乖儿子  警探
You got a great kid here, Detective.
我发誓  你敢动他一根汗毛  我会杀了你
I swear to god, if you touch him I'll kill you.
你有办法救回他
You have the means to set him free.
你没法呼叫支援
You can't call for backup.
你还能相信谁呢
Who you gonna trust anymore?
你知道我不能把他们交给你
You know I can't hand these guys over to you.
那等于亲手杀了他们
I might as well kill them myself.
你如果这么做  那可帮了我一个大忙
If you're up to it, that would be extremely helpful.
你为什么要那些老大们死  以利亚
Why do you need the bosses dead, Elias?
你已经展示了你的威力
You've already shown how powerful you are.
你不明白自己在保护何等的魔鬼  是吗
You don't understand the evil you're protecting, do you?
让我帮你普及一下桑布拉诺的知识
Let me tell you something about Zambrano.
他靠向学生卖海洛因为生
He earns his living by selling heroin to schoolchildren.
格里福尼贩卖枪支  谁出钱给谁
Grifoni sells guns to the highest bidder.
我那道貌岸然同父异母的弟弟
My esteemed half-brother,
他不仅经手毒品
a man who not only imports drugs,
还贩卖少女
but young girls.
那就是你在保护的人
These are the men that you are protecting.
你管辖之下  一切都会更美好吗
Things would be much better under your watch, huh?
我掌管的组织高效运转
I run an efficient enterprise.
没有内讧  没有地盘争夺
There's no infighting, there's no conflict over territory.
我是有组织犯罪的进化版
I am the evolution of organized crime.
你堕落和懦弱的推动者
You're a force of corruption and weakness.
我的回答是  不
My answer is no.
他想要用泰勒换黑帮头目们
He wants to trade Taylor for the Dons.
-我怎么可以  -你不可以
- How can I do that? - You can't.
但你不必做出取舍
But you don't have to make that decision,
因为我会把你儿子救回来
Because I'm gonna get your son back.
不惜一切代价
No matter what the cost.
我不会让任何人伤害他
I won't let anyone hurt him.
明白吗  卡特
You hear me, Carter?
你保证
Promise me.
我发誓
You have my word.
芬奇  告诉我去哪里找那男孩
Finch, I need you to tell me where to find the boy.
已经在找了  里瑟先生
I'm a step ahead of you, Mr. Reese.
找到泰勒的唯一办法就是和魔鬼做交易
The only way to locate Taylor is to make a deal with the devil
我希望你指的不是以利亚
I hope you're not referring to Elias.
以利亚并非联络名单上唯一的堕落天使
Elias isn't the only fallen angel in our rolodex,
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
你还好吗  卡特
You okay, Carter?
他们抓走了我儿子
They got my kid.
你确定不要支援来这里吗
You sure not calling backup's the way to go here?
你不明白  弗斯科
You don't get it, Fusco.
看到穿西装的那两个人了吗
You see those two in the suits?
他们是15局风化组的
They work VICE at the 15th.
他们在这儿是为了帮以利亚
They're here to help Elias,
不是支援我们
not back us up.
你想要怎么做
What do you wanna do?
等着
Wait.
确保这里已经完全封锁
Make sure this place is sealed off.
行  我去彻底检查一下
Okay. I'll do a sweep,
保证这儿滴水不漏
and make sure it's airtight.
你应该是我们的领路人  卡特警探
You should have been our wheel-man, Detective Carter.
但你的搭档令人不敢恭维
I don't think your partner had it in him.
别去怪弗斯科  与他无关
Don't go blaming Fusco, this isn't on him.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
我可是隐约记得
Because I got this vague recollection...
你的搭档以前拿过脏钱
that your partner used to be on the take.
实际上  我再仔细想想
In fact now that I think about it,
就完全确定了
I'm sure of it.
他以前和那个  斯蒂尔斯警探合作  是吧
He was partners with that, Detective Stills, right?
那个涉嫌贪污  失踪数月的警察
That dirty cop who went missing a few months back?
那些人在城里的各种勾当中都插了一脚
Those guys had their paws around every game in town.
他们全都拿过脏钱
All of them on the take.
他们无所谓  因为只要扔些烂仔进去
And they didn't care because they'd just throw a piece upstairs
什么低层的毒贩啦  皮条客啦
you know, shaking down low-life drug dealers, pimps,
无所不用其极
whatever scratch they could get.
他们甚至搞过暗杀
They even did some wet work.
你好  警探
Hello, Detective.
我亲自来谈谈
I've come to talk it over in person.
你选好边站了吗
Are you ready to pick the right side?
你好  西蒙斯警官
Hello, Officer Simmons.
我能否占用你几分钟时间
I wonder if I might have a few minutes of your time.
你是什么人
Who the hell are you?
告诉我你是谁  还是要我逮捕你
You gonna tell me who you are or do I have to arrest you?
我想和你谈谈你的组织
I'd like to talk to you about your organization.
就是俗称的HR
The one commonly referred to as HR.
我注意到HR被一大笔钱收买
It's come to my attention that HR has been paid
从而对所有牵涉到
a large sum of money to ignore
以利亚这个人的犯罪活动都视而不见
any criminal activities involving a man named Elias.
是吗
Really?
你又是怎么注意到这个消息的
And how exactly did this come to your attention?
我会注意到一些事  警官
I notice things, officer.
一些被其他人忽视的事
Things the rest of the world ignores.
我还注意到一些关于以利亚的事
And I've noticed things about Elias
我相信你一定忽视了
that I believe you've overlooked.
我可不信
I doubt that.
我的洞察力相当不错
I'm a pretty observant guy myself.
你以为以利亚代表了
You think Elias stands for a return
旧规则的回归
to the way things used to be.
一个组织控制所有的黑帮
A firm hand on the reins of organized crime.
但他同时也代表了别的东西
But he also stands for other things.
这是以利亚对HR警官
This is Elias's surveillance of HR police officers
及他们家人的监控照片
and their families.
你在与魔鬼共舞
You're in bed with the devil.
此人为达目的  不择手段
This man will go to any length to get what he wants,
甚至不惜绑架儿童
including kidnapping children.
卡特警探的儿子只是他最新的受害人
Detective Carter's son is only his most recent victim.
我没听说过这个
I didn't hear anything about that.
我知道  警官  我现在
Look, I recognize, Officer, that I'm placing myself
跟你同桌而坐是在拿自己冒险
in danger by sitting here with you.
我希望你明白  你现在
I need you to understand that you're placing
跟以利亚做交易是在拿你的家人冒险
your family in danger by doing business with Elias.
这是什么东西
What the hell is this?
监视你妻子的人前科累累
The man following your wife is an ex-con
他的主要罪名包括强奸  过失杀人
whose prior convictions include rape, manslaughter...
以利亚牢牢控制着你和你的家人
Elias is keeping you and yours in check...
直到他的计划得以完成
Until his plan is finished.
而完成之后
After that...
他对你是否有别的打算就不得而知了
who knows whether he'll have any use for you.
我怎么知道这个人不是你的手下
How do I know this guy doesn't work for you, huh?
我想你不知道
I imagine you don't.
但你真的愿意拿你家人的生命当赌注吗
But are you really willing to bet your family's life on it?
你想怎么样
What do you want?
帮我找到关押卡特警探儿子的地方
You need to get me the location of Detective Carter's son.
然后撤掉你手下为以利亚卖命的所有人
Call off any men you have working on Elias's behalf.
从此刻开始  HR与以利亚一刀两断
HR severs its ties with Elias as of this moment.
我可不会在这等上整晚  警探
Not gonna wait all night, detective.
放了他  以利亚
Let him go, Elias.
他与此事无关
He's got no part in this.
泰勒看起来是个不错的小伙子
Taylor seems like a very nice young man.
我也不想伤害他
I'd rather not hurt him.
你必须接受现实
You need to accept the fact
没人会来救你的  你在孤军奋战
that no one's coming to save you -- you are all alone.
我想  我想就在那边了
I think -- I think it's right up over here.
简直比带上黄铜胸罩的巫婆奶头还冷
Colder than a witch's nip in a brass bra.
莫雷蒂头目在哪儿
Where's Don Moretti?
你说呢  小子
Yeah, you tell me, kid.
老大让我转告你
Well, the boss wanted me to tell you
他也希望他能来
he wished he could be here...
但是他有事来不了了
but he couldn't make it.
-走吧  -说到黄铜[厚颜无耻]
- Come on.  - Talk about brass.
以前那些头目们都是自己擦屁股的
Used to be the Dons would clean up their own mess.
莫雷蒂根本没种过来
Moretti didn't have the stones to be here.
德卢卡告诉我
You know, Deluca told me
他以前让他把那娘们儿干掉
he made him get rid of the broad back in the day.
现在又让我们来处理这倒霉杂种
Now we gotta deal with this miserable bastard.
搞什么名堂
For crying out loud.
这家伙还哭上了
Here come the waterworks.
怎么着  小子
What's the matter, kid?
不是你期待的阖家团聚吗
Not the family reunion you were hoping for?
我真蠢呀  我早该想到了
What an idiot, I should have known.
是啊  头目已经有了一个傻逼儿子了
Yeah, well, the Don's already got one idiot kid.
我猜他也不需要第二个了
Guess he didn't need another one.
你俩觉得自己很安全  因为是两个对一个
You two think you're safe because there's just one of me.
我很弱  你们俩却很壮
That I'm weak and that you're strong.
那不是力量
That's not strength.
而是软弱
That's weakness.
看看你们  两个心怀嫉妒的蠢货
Look at you...a bunch of jealous idiots.
背叛彼此的骗子
Liars, betraying each other.
我不需要这些
I don't need that.
我的力量源自孤寂
I get my strength from being alone,
我将以此毁掉你们所有人
and that's why I'm gonna destroy all of you.
把他的嘴给我堵上  行不
Shut him up already, will ya?
拜托  帮个忙呀  小杂种
Come on, help me out! Little bastard!
这就是他们囚禁泰勒的地方
This is where they're holding Taylor.
你有什么计划  约翰
What's your plan, John?
没有计划
No plan.
我就准备单刀直入
I'll just take the direct approach.
抱歉我在这方面就帮不上什么忙了
I'm sorry I'm not much use on this end of things.
这样吧
Look...
教我怎么用枪  我就可以帮得上忙了
show me how to fire one of these and I can help.
我可以
I'll...
转移他们的注意力  或者
create a distraction, I suppose, or...
别担心  哈罗德
That's okay, Harold.
你可以当我的接应司机
You can be the getaway driver.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
再说了  你知道我最恨有人对孩子下手
Besides, you know I don't like it when people mess with kids
最后一次机会了  警探
Last chance, detective.
邪恶腐败的家伙们  还是你无辜的儿子
Those immoral, corrupt men or your innocent son.
做梦
No deal.
-你准备怎么办  -我就守在这
- What are you gonna do?  - I'm staying right here.
他们别想从我这过去
They're not getting past me.
我并不如你所想的那般孤军奋战
I'm not as alone as you think!
-你没事吧  -没事
- Are you okay?  - Yeah.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫约翰
My name is John.
你妈妈派我来的
Your mother sent me.
你是来救我的
You here to rescue me?
还是来杀我的
Or shoot me?
今晚
Tonight...
救人
rescue.
卡特
Carter.
那些HR警察走了
Those HR cops just took off.
把那些头目们护在后面
Keep the Dons in the back.
你耳聋啦  退后
Hey, you heard the lady. Get back.
开门  警探
Open the door, detective.
我早该猜到了
I should have known.
说什么要跟以利亚分一杯羹
All that nonsense about bringing Elias into the fold.
你简直是耻辱  内鬼
You're an embarrassment! A rat!
以利亚给出的条件很好
Elias offered me a deal.
识时务者为俊杰
When change comes, you gotta adapt.
你和你老爸  从来就不懂
You and your old man, you never learned that lesson.
把枪放下  桑布拉诺
Drop it, Zambrano.
你先放我出去
Not until you let me out of here.
你就应该乖乖听以利亚的话
You should have given Elias everything he wanted
就像其他警察一样
like the rest of them.
我不会睁只眼闭只眼
I don't look the other way.
是啊  可是你的搭档会
Yeah, but your partner does.
对吧
Right...
弗斯科
Fusco?
你很清楚  三十秒后  这个城市
You see, in less than 30 seconds there's a guy
未来的话事人就会冲进来
that's gonna come into this room that's gonna run this city.
你是识时务的
You're a survivor.
你要选对边站
You gonna choose the right side?
还是跟你的搭档一起死在这
Or are you gonna die alone here with your partner?
站住  以利亚
Not one more step, Elias.
叫你的手下把枪放下
Tell your boys to put down their weapons...
不然他们的下场就会跟那边的桑布拉诺一样
or their day will end like Zambrano's over here.
你的工作很出色  警探
You're good at your job, detective.
我的工作也一样
I'm good at mine.
我希望我们能避免更多的流血事件
I was hoping we could avoid further bloodshed.
这就是结局了
This is where it ends.
此地  此时
Right here, right now.
我叫了支援
I called for backup.
你总得信任某些人  卡特
You gotta trust somebody, Carter.
这家伙并没有买通所有的警察
This guy doesn't own every cop.
趴下  趴下
Get down, get down!
卡尔・以利亚  你被捕了
Carl Elias, you are under arrest.
至于你的罪名  我得回头慢慢算
I'll have to check my notes for the list of charges,
但是首要的就是谋杀和绑架
but murder and kidnapping are at the top.
你是无法改变历史的必然  警探
You can't stop the inevitable, detective.
不管你接受与否  改变总是会发生的
Change will happen whether you embrace it or not.
我父亲在哪里
Where is my father.
你死定了
You're dead.
甚至不会有人记得你曾活过
No one's ever gonna remember you even existed!
你一无是处  听见了吗
You're nothing, you hear me?
-说话  -妈妈  是我
- Talk to me.  - Mom, it's me.
泰勒  你没事吧
Taylor. Are you okay?
你派过来的这个人可真不是好惹的
That guy you sent is kind of a bad-ass.
是啊  他自己也知道
Yeah, he knows it too.
那个戴眼镜的人是谁
Who's the guy with the glasses?
如果你发现了  别忘了告诉我
If you find out, let me know.
你在哪
Where are you?
我很安全
I'm safe.
待会见
I'll see you soon.
好吧
Okay.
很高兴你遵守了誓言
Good to know you keep your promises.
我说过  我不会让你儿子出事的
I told you I'd never let anything happen to your son.
谢谢
Thank you.
眼镜摘掉
Glasses off.
出生日期
Birth date?
1965年8月18日
August 18, 1965.
社保号码
Social security number?
306003894
306-00-3894.
你回来真好  爸爸
It's good to have you back, pop.
回来真好
It's good to be back.
回家吧  儿子
Let's go home, son.
喂
Hello?
你好  爸爸
Hi, dad.
你以为这样就能吓到我吗
What, is this somehow supposed to intimidate me?
我只是想跟你道个别
I just wanted to say good-bye...
真希望我能在现场
and that I wish I could have been there.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第19集
Person of Interest S01E19 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-